Guide to the Michael Arad 9/11 Memorial Papers 2001-2019 PR 422
New-York Historical Society
- Series III: Ephemera and Other Media, 2001-2019
  - Informational Cards, Stickers, etc., 9/11 Memorial, undated (Offsite-box 32, Folder 5-6)
  - Magazine, "Lifestyles", 2004 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 7)
  - Magazine, "Men's Journal", 2007 September (Offsite-box 32, Folder 8)
  - Magazine, "Esposus", 2014 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 9)
  - Magazine, "Kulturautausch", 2016 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 10)
  - Manuscript (partial), "A Place of Remembrance", 2011 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 11)
  - News Articles about WTC Memorial site, 2003-2012 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 12-13)
  - News Articles about WTC Memorial site, 2003-2005 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 9)
  - Newspapers and Magazines, 2001-2012 (Offsite-box 45)
    Mostly New York publications containing articles related to the 9/11 terrorist attacks and the 9/11 Memorial.
  - Poster, Art Aid, 2004 (Folder FF11)
  - Poster, Carnegie Corporation (features Arad), 2012 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 6)
  - Poster, Downtown Alliance, undated (Folder FF2)
  - Poster, Downtown Alliance on foam core, undated (Folder FF11)
  - Sheet Music, "One World: Sketches for Orchestra", 2019 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 14)
  - VHS Tape, LMDC Memorial Competition, undated (Offsite-box 32, Folder 15)
  - VHS Tape, WTC Design, undated (Offsite-box 32, Folder 16)
  - VHS Tape, Dartmouth Convocation (2 copies), 2004 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 17)
  - Other - Ephemera from Museums and Memorials (not WTC), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 13)
  - Other - Ephemera from Museums and Memorials (not WTC), undated (Offsite-box 44, Folder 8)
- Series IV: Images - Photographs and Prints, 2007, undated
  This series includes film and digital photographic prints of the 9/11 Memorial design and construction, as well as images of Michael Arad and other people at the World Trade Center site and at various other sites. It also includes a framed collage of three photographs of Ground Zero and one Certificate of Copyright for the photo "The Cathedral," which is signed and inscribed to Michael Arad.
  - Arad's Photographs, undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 6A)
  - Arad's Photographs, 1987-2005 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 11)
  - Photographs and Prints of World Trade Center Memorial Designs and Design Elements, undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 7-13)
  - Photographs and Prints of World Trade Center Memorial Designs and Design Elements, undated (Offsite-box 44, Folder 12)
  - Photographs and Prints of the Names Parapet, undated (Offsite-box 26, Folder 8)
  - Photographs of the 9/11 Memorial, undated (Offsite-box 33, Folder 3)
  - Portrait, Michael Arad, undated (Offsite-box 33, Folder 2)
  - Renderings, 2005 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 17)
  - Renderings, 2007 July (Offsite-box 2, Folder 14)
  - Renderings, undated (Offsite-box 50)
  - West, Eugene. Framed collage of three photographs of Ground Zero and one Certificate of Copyright. One photo is titled "The Cathedral," and is signed., 2001-2002 (Folder FF12)
- Series V: Names Parapet, 2004-2010
  This series consists of material that documents the creation of the Names Parapet, one of the most difficult challenges in the design of the 9/11 Memorial. The names of the 2,982 individuals killed in the attacks of September 11, 2001 and the bombing on February 26, 1993 are inscribed in bronze around the perimeters of the Memorial pools, which are located in the footprints of the Twin Towers. The names are arranged by where victims were and who they were with, and further requests for specific names to be located next to one another were made by the families of those who were lost.
  The series is largely made up of scrolls and strips of paper with various arrangements of the names of the victims.
  - Names - Text Calculations, 2004 September- 2004 October (Offsite-box 26, Folder 1)
  - Names - Markers: Recognition and Arrangement, 2005 September 20 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 2)
  - Names - Markers: Victim Information: Mapping, 2006 January 19 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 3)
  - Names - Markers: Recognition and Arrangement, 2006 March (Offsite-box 26, Folder 4)
  - Names: Markers: Recognition and Arrangement, 2006-2010 (Offsite-box 50)
  - Names: Markers: Recognition and Arrangement, 2008-2010 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 13-15)
  - Names - Parapet Fountain Studies, 2006 September 6 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 5)
  - Names - Parapet Fountain Studies, 2006 November 14 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 6)
  - Names - Parapet, 2007 (Offsite-box 26, Folder 7)
  - Names - Parapet, 2008 January-2008 April (Offsite-box 27, Folder 1)
  - Names - Parapet, 2009-2010 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 16-17)
  - Names - Parapet Sight Lines, 2008 May (Offsite-box 27, Folder 2)
  - Names - Parapet, 2008 July 9 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 3)
  - Names - Parapet Studies, 2008 September 25 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 4)
  - Names - Parapet Studies, 2008 October (Offsite-box 27, Folder 5)
  - Names - Parapet Studies Options, 2008 November (Offsite-box 27, Folder 6)
  - Names - Parapet Studies, 2009 (Offsite-box 27, Folder 7)
  - Names - Scrolls, 2009-2010 (Offsite-box 28)
  - Names - Scrolls, 2009-2010 (Offsite-box 29)
  - Names - Scrolls, 2009-2010 (Offsite-box 33)
  - Names - Scrolls and Strips, 2009-2010 (Offsite-box 30)
  - Names - Strips Arranged in Marked Envelopes, undated (Offsite-box 32, Folder 18-22)
  - Names - Scrolls and Strips, undated (Folder FF3)
- Series VI: Office Files, 2003-2019
  This series consists of documents related to the design and construction of the National September 11 Memorial. It contains correspondence, including print outs of email, billing information, and contracts. The files also occasionally include small drawings, rough sketches, specifications, and clippings.
  Arrangement
  The series is arranged into three subseries based on its original order as received by N-YHS:
  Arad's Files
  Davis Bond Brody Files (Davis Brody Bond LLP was chosen by LMDC as the Associate Architect for the World Trade Center Memorial.)
  Project Files
  - Subseries VI.A: Arad Files
    - Competition and Early Design Planning, 2003-2004 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1-3)
    - Competition and Early Design Planning, 2003-2004 (Offsite-box 36, Folder 1-12)
    - Correspondence, 2003-2019 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
      Consists mainly of people's reactions to the design of the memorial, both before and after it was completed. Some letters address how best to memorialize the individuals killed on 9/11.
    - Correspondence, 2003-2005 (Offsite-box 36, Folder 13)
    - Dartmouth Convocation, 2004 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
      Material related to the convocation address given by Michael Arad at Datmouth on September 21, 2004. Includes a copy of the speech, correspondence, programs, and photographs.
    - Invitations and Events, 2004-2015 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6-7)
    - Project Files, 2003-Jul 2004 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
    - Project Files, Jan-Oct 2004 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 1-11)
    - Project Files, Aug 2004 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
    - Project Files, Sept 2004 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 10-11)
    - Project Files, Oct-Dec 2004 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 12)
    - Project Files, Oct-Dec 2004 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 1-3)
    - Project Files, Jan-Sept 2005 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 4-13)
    - Project Files, Oct-Dec 2005 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 1-2)
    - Project Files, 2005 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
    - Project Files, 2006 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 4-8)
    - Project Files, 2006-2007 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
    - Project Files, 2007-2011 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 9)
    - Project Files, 2008-2018 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 3)
    - Project Manual, vol. 1-3, 2004 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 11)
    - Project Notebook, 2004-2006 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 10)
    - Printouts of Email Correspondence, Sep-Oct 2003 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 4)
    - Printouts of Email Correspondence, Nov 2003 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 5)
    - Printouts of Email Correspondence, Dec 2003-Mar 2004 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 6)
    - Other Files, 2005, undated (Offsite-box 36, Folder 14-16)
  - Subseries VI.B: Davis Brody Bond Files, 2004-2005
    This series consists of files related to the firm of Davis Brody Bond, the Associate Architects who worked with Michael Arad and Peter Walker, Design Lead Architects, on the WTC Memorial.
    - Associate Architect Request for Proposal, 2004 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 1-2)
    - Davis Brody Bond, Associate Architects, 2004 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 3-4)
    - Davis Brody Bond, Associate Architects, 2005 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 5-9)
    - Davis Brody Bond, Associate Architects, 2005 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 18)
  - Subseries VI.C: Project Files - National September 11 Memorial
    - Acoustical Design Report, 2005 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 1)
    - Acoustical Design Report, 2005 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 1)
    - Agendas, 2004-2005 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 2)
    - Budget Estimates, 2004 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 2-3)
    - Budget Estimates, 2004-2005 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 3)
    - Budget Estimates, 2005 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 4-6)
    - Budget Estimates, 2006-2007 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 7)
    - City and State Agency Documents, 2004-2008 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 4)
    - Client Files-LMDC, 2004 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 6-10)
    - Client Files-LMDC, 2004 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 8-9)
    - Client Files-LMDC, 2005 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 11)
    - Client Files-LMDC, 2005 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 10)
    - Client Files-LMDC, 2006 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 12)
    - Client Files-LMDC, 2006 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 11)
    - Commercial Design Guidelines, 2004 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 1)
    - Contracts, 2004 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 5-6)
    - Contracts, 2004 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 12)
    - Contracts, 2005 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 7)
    - Contracts, 2005 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 13-14)
    - Contracts, 2006 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 8)
    - Contracts, 2006 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 15)
    - Contracts-Code Consultants, 2004 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9)
    - Cultural Center Design, 2005-2006 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 10)
    - Draft Specifications, 2006 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 2-4)
    - Draft Specifications-Design Development Phase, 2005 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 18)
    - Envelope Definition Package, 2004 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 5)
    - Financial, 2004 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 16)
    - Fire and Egress Studies, 2005 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 6-7)
    - Footings and Foundations Specifications, 2005 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 8)
    - Insurance, 2004-2005 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 1)
    - Invoices, 2004 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 11)
    - Invoices, 2004 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 2-4)
    - Invoices, 2005 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 12)
    - Invoices, 2005 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 5)
    - Invoices, 2006 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 13-14)
    - Invoices, 2006 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 6)
    - Invoices, 2007 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 15)
    - Invoices, 2008 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 16)
    - Landscaping, 2004 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 7-8)
    - Landscaping, 2005 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 17)
    - Landscaping, 2005 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 9)
    - Legal, 2004 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 10)
    - Lighting Proposals, 2004 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 11)
    - Lighting, 2004-2005 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 18)
    - LMDC Presentation, 2004 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 9)
    - Master Plan, 2004 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 12)
    - Materials, 2004 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 13)
    - Mechanical, Electrical and Plumbing, 2004-2005 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 19)
    - Meeting Minutes and Agendas, 2004 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 20)
    - Meeting Minutes and Agendas, 2004-2005 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 14-15)
    - Meeting Minutes and Agendas, 2005 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 21)
    - Meeting Minutes and Agendas, 2005-2006 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 1)
    - MEP/Utilities, 2004 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 16)
    - Models, 2004 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 1)
    - Names on Memorial, 2002-2011 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 2-5)
    - Names on Memorial, 2003-2011 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 2-3)
    - Names Parapet Fountain, 2004-2005 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 6-10)
    - Operations, 2004 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 4)
    - Operations, 2004-2005 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 11-12)
    - Operations, 2005 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 5)
    - Press, 2005 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 13)
    - Project Manual Vol.1-3, 2004 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 10-12)
    - Programming, 2004-2005 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 14)
    - Schematic Design Meeting, 2004 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 5)
    - Section 106, National Historic Preservation Act, 2004 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 6)
    - Site Security Issues, 2004-2005 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 7)
    - Site Signage, 2004-2005 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 8)
    - Space Requirements/Design, 2004 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 9)
    - Staffing, 2002-2004 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 10)
    - Status Reports, 2004 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 15)
    - Status Reports, 2004-2006 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 11)
    - Structural, 2004 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 12)
    - Subcontractors-STV, 2004 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 13)
    - Sustainability, 2004-2005 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 14)
    - Timesheets, 2004 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 16)
    - Traffic, 2005 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 15)
    - Waterproofing, 2005 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 16)
    - Wind Conditions, 2005 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 17)
    - Work Orders, 2004-2006 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 18)
    - Work Schedule, 2004 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 19)
- Series VII: Site Models and Objects, undated
  This series contains one intact model, boxes of models components, several sculptural pieces, sample names panels, and five hard hats with 9/11 Memorial insignia on them.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Models are restricted due to their fragility. Special permission to view the models must be received from both the curator and the chief conservator. All requests must be made in advance and in writing.
  - WTC Memorial Model "Reflecting Absence", undated (Offsite-box Bin3)
  - WTC Memorial Model Pieces 1, undated (Offsite-box Bin1, Box Objects 1)
  - WTC Memorial Model Pieces 2, undated (Offsite-box Bin1, Box Objects 2)
  - WTC Memorial Sculptural Pieces and Letters, undated (Offsite-box Bin1, Box Objects 3)
  - WTC Memorial Sculptural Pieces and Name Panel Samples, undated (Offsite-box Bin1, Box Objects 4)
  - WTC Site Model and One World Trade Center Sculpture, undated (Offsite-box Bin1, Box Objects 5)
  - WTC Memorial Model Pieces 3, undated (Offsite-box Bin1, Box Objects 6)
  - WTC Memorial Models Pieces 4, undated (Offsite-box Bin2, Box Objects 7)
  - WTC Memorial Model Pieces 5, undated (Offsite-box Bin2, Box Objects 8)
  - WTC Memorial Name Panel Samples, undated (Offsite-box Bin2, Box Objects 9)
  - WTC Memorial Name Panel Samples, undated (Offsite-box 55)
  - WTC Memorial Name Panel Samples, undated (Offsite-box 56)
  - WTC Memorial Name Panel Samples, undated (Offsite-box 57)
  - WTC Memorial Name Panel Samples, undated (Offsite-box 58)
  - Hardhats from WTC Memorial Site, undated (Offsite-box Bin2, Box Objects 10)
- Series VIII: Other Projects (not WTC), 2004-2007
  This series contains material that is unrelated to the 9/11 Memorial. It mainly consists of plans for a Handel Architects building on 255 Hudson Street in New York City.
  - Project 392.01: 255 Hudson Street, 2004-2007 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 1-12)
  - Various Projects, Handel Architects, 2004-2007 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 13)